SACHIN AHUJA

sachinahi@gmail.com | sachinahuja.info | New York, NY

FULL-STACK/DATA ENGINEER

Software engineering expert with 7 years of committed client service in business intelligence and data analytic applications. Specializes in software development and data engineering functions. Spearheads and drives a multitude of high-profile research and data analytics projects. Driven to find technical and data-centered solutions for companies' greatest challenges in an effort to add value. Serves as a leader in the mentoring and coaching of other team members by teaching techniques, processes, and applications used in data management.

CORE PROFICIENCIES

Data Engineering | Amazon Web Services | Product Management | Project Implementation | Project Management Web & Application Development | Troubleshooting | Process Improvement | End-User and Customer Support

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCES

BETTER.COM

Senior Software Engineer

2019 — Present

FORTNITECLIPZ

Founder 2018 — 2020

- FortniteClipz was a web app that automatically created highlights of Twitch.tv Fortnite streams by using machine learning/artificial intelligence to recognize when key moments happen during a stream
- The backend was built using AWS serverless infrastructure, including IAM, CloudFormation, RDS, S3, API Gateway, Lambda, SQS, MediaConvert, Cloudwatch, and Cognito
- Services use FFmpeg and FFprobe to analyze and manipulate video streams
- The web client was built using React with Google Analytics

ATOM TICKETS

Data Engineer 2018 — 2019

- Architected ETL streaming pipelines using Confluent/Kakfa/Debezium/ECS to create a real-time change data capture (CDC) process from MySQL to Snowflake
- Collaborated with the Customer Service team to launch an automated Weekly Business Review with CSAT, SLA, etc. metrics by ingesting data from Zendesk/UJET and creating dashboards in Looker
- Developed ETL batch and Spark streaming jobs using Scala/Airflow/EMR
- Managed ETL batch pipelines using Python/ECS to create a batch change data capture (CDC) process from MySQL to Redshift
- Ingested data into Redshift from Braintree's Java SDK using Airflow and created Views/Model in Looker to help audit transaction data against Atom's books
- Worked with the Business, Product, and Marketing teams to build third party data exchanges as per partner agreements

Software Design Engineer

2017 - 2018

- Engineered a revolutionary, user-friendly, and socially-driven interface that allows movie lovers to search for films
 instantly, invite friends, buy tickets, pre-order concessions and enjoy a VIP experience at the theater
- Assisted with the application planning, development, and deployment of Atom's and Regal's web clients using Scala,
 Play Framework, and JavaScript

- Integrated Google Pay and Chase Pay into the checkout flow assuring higher user conversion
- Reviewed and implemented special partnership promotions to help increase traffic with Amazon Prime and Lionsgate/AMEX exclusive screenings, decreasing CPA by 26%
- Implemented advertisement placements with Adzerk support to manage scheduling and goal tracking
- Led the development of ADA compliance for Regal Cinemas

VISA

Senior UI Engineer

2016 - 2017

- Charged with enhancing the UI implementation in a forward-thinking, reusable, and scalable UI architecture
- Designed React web components taken from prototypes, partnering exclusively with design, engineering, and product teams to ensure project alignment
- Developed the following web components, resulting in streamlined user experience:
 Advanced Search, Advanced Dropdown, Date-Time Picker, Status, Status Manager
- Collaborated to author documentation for the reusable web components open-sourced within the company
- Increased the coverage of the UI unit testing framework to 85% using Enzyme

DRAFTCRUNCH

Lead Software Developer (engineering team of two)

2015 - 2016

- Partnered with the co-founders to build venture-backed sports analytics platform for daily fantasy sports players to create, sell, and/or purchase third-party predictive models and strategies acquiring 15,000 users
- Engineered a web service, with cached architecture, master-slave cluster, and sticky sessions for web-sockets to create the fastest responsive lineup builder in the industry
- Developed the Lineup Builder web client using Angular.js, which serves as a complex analytical tool to analyze and create lineups
- Directed flow of assignments by delegating sub-tasks to team members and contractors, monitoring project progress along the way
- Created ETL services integrated with 3rd party APIs and web scrapers to acquire the latest information for the platform
- Crafted an image rendering microservice for social sharing of lineups to create virality
- Managed production bottlenecks, performed unit testing, and test drove development, ensuring maximum quality assurance during every phase of development

TOGGA

Web Developer (engineering team of three)

2014 - 2015

- Produced the first Women's World Cup fantasy app, acquiring 110,000 users, using Ionic.js and Node.js microservices deployed on Docker
- Contributed to building high-performance cloud-based REST API services, handling 30,000 daily active users using Node.js, PHP, MySQL and Redis
- Enhanced the Draft app from end to end by configuring a microservice to manage scheduled events and incorporated real-time data support using Firebase
- Spearheaded the migration of the web client architecture from jQuery to Angular.js
- Programmed an email campaign manager to augment retention by sending out weekly emails to users
- Incorporated analytics and created scripts to determine power users using Google Analytics and MixPanel

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

| Programming Bootcamp and Coding School | MakerSquare | - | Austin, TX | | 2014 |
|--|---------------------------------|---|-------------|--------|--------|
| Bachelor of Science in Chemical Engineering | Georgia Institute of Technology | - | Atlanta, GA | 2009 – | - 2013 |

TECHNICAL PROFICIENCIES

CI/CD

| TECHNICAL PRO | TICLEVELES | | | | |
|---------------------|---|--|--|--|--|
| JAVASCRIPT | AngularJS, Handlebars.js, Ionic, jQuery, Meteor, Node.js, React, Underscore.js, Zepto.js | | | | |
| AMAZON WEB SERVICES | API Gateway, CloudFormation, CloudFront, CloudWatch, Cognito, DynamoDB, EC2, ECR, ECS, Elastic Beanstalk, Elastic Transcoder, IAM, Kinesis, Lambda, MSK, MediaConvert, RDS, Route 53, S3, SNS, SQS, VPC | | | | |
| DATA | Airflow, Confluent, Debezium, Kafka, Looker, Spark | | | | |
| DATABASE | ActiveRecord, DynamoDB, MesaSQLite, MongoDB, MySQL, NoSQL, PostgreSQL, RDS, Redshift, RoboMongo, SQLite3, SequelPro, Snowflake | | | | |
| OTHER | DApps/Solidity, Docker, FFmpeg/FFprobe, Golang, Java, Kali Linux (Aircrack-ng), Play Framework, Ruby on Rails, Scala, Serverless Framework, Swift, Xamarin | | | | |
| WEB | ■ Bootstrap, Foundation, Grunt, Gulp.js, Less, Sass, SCSS, Webpack | | | | |
| APP ANALYTICS | ■ DataDog, LogDNA, Loggly, New Relic, Optimizely, PagerDuty, Rollbar, Wasabi | | | | |
| CUSTOMER ANALYTICS | Customer.io, Facebook Pixel, FullStory, Google Analytics, Mixpanel, Segment | | | | |
| ENGAGEMENT | Adzerk, Appcues, Branch, Braze, Intercom, Tawk.to | | | | |
| MANAGEMENT | ■ Bitbucket, Confluence, GitHub, JIRA, Rally, Slack, Trello | | | | |
| NPM | async, cluster, cron, express, moment, mongodb, MySQL, request, rxjs, socket.io, zerorpc, zmq | | | | |
| PIP | ffprobe3, matplotlib, numpy, opencv-python, pandas, pillow, pytesseract, requests, seaborn, streamlink, tensorflow | | | | |

Bamboo , Buildkite, Jenkins, Travis Cl